[Music]
Welcome back to William Northwest. If
you love shopping at garage and estate
sales, our first guest wants to help
help you narrow your shirt search down.
Here to share things you should always
look for, we welcome back antique
appraiser Gary Gurmer. And also, this
is kind of a 101 for beginning uh garage
salers or if you've never been to an
estate sale or a garage sale. >> Yeah. And
you kind of want to go, what's the hubhub
about? Quick, quickly, the difference
between a garage sale and an estate
sale. >> Whoa, whoa, whoa. Oh, that was
close, Gary. That was close. >> This is
why they have me on television is to do
things like that, you know. >> But you
save the day. You save the day. >> I'll
quit gesturing as much. The difference
between an estate sale and a garage sale.
An estate sale generally implies somebody
passed away or maybe they moved and
they're selling everything. >> Sure.
They're downsizing. Yeah. >> Garage sale is
people getting rid of the junk they
don't want. Right. So most of the time
you'll find your best deals, your best
treasures at an estate sale. Estate deal
much things much broader things to look
at and you know to get really into it
you want to it's about knowledge and what
do you know and the more things you're
interested in you'll learn more about
it. >> Sure. >> And then you'll become an
expert and then you'll develop an eye to
go for these things. >> But just a few
things. One of the first things you want
to look at and take your time with is
gold and silver. >> Gold and silver.
So here we go. >> You can make a lot of
money with gold and silver. And people
often times figure grandma's good jewelry
is in the safe. And so we you have your
choice of this jewelry three bucks a
piece. The two tools you need are a loop.
Go buy this if you don't 10 power or
stronger >> and a a good magnet. >>
Magnet. >> So you see pieces most of
them will be marked if
it's a costumeum monet
like we were talking earlier about the
u ring the jew the diamond ring. Okay.
>> Well, you look at that and it says
that it's gold filled on it and then uh
you see the diamonds are pressed in. The
light's not going all the way through.
That can kind of tell you it's not
really good. And you hit it with your um
magnet and it and it is working. It's not
going to be gold. So, that's not gold.
>> But that clears. So, you know those
are not diamonds and not gold. >> So, you
go through here, you see a bunch of
costume jewelry. You're then you see this
one here. It's marked 14 karat gold.
Oh my god. You've scored. You got this
great big piece. This is where your magnet
actually comes in and you can pick it
up with a magnet. >> So that means it
is gold. >> It's not gold. >> It's not
gold. >> Gold is non-magnetic. >> Okay.
So then this is gold. >> No. No. It's
when it says that it's not gold. If it
if it's not magnetic, it means that it it
if it is magnetic, it's definitely not.
If it's not magnetic, it possibly is
gold. >> I see. That's when you use your
loop. >> That's when you want to really
look at it closer. >> Okay. I misunderstand.
go through here and it's the same
sort of thing. Gold and this one's marked
18 karat. >> We hit it. >> It's not
gold. >> I mean, it's not uh magnetic.
>> 18 karat. Chances are it's gold. Spend
three bucks on this. You'll end up getting
$1,300 worth of gold in your pocket.
Wow. >> So, it's a little bit If you
want to learn more, there's a lot of
YouTube videos that can give you even
more detailed on how to look for >> how to
do that. Okay. You also Oh, go ahead.
Sorry. No, go ahead. >> One of the things
I This is just a silly thing of mine.
I buy little children's books in really
great condition because I have friends
who have babies and grandkids and kids
that come over and I don't pay but two
to three bucks a piece. I have a a couple
that are dear friends of mine are having
a baby. By the time the baby comes
that's going to have the biggest library
you've ever seen >> because you've got
all these great books for them. >> Get
books for next to nothing >> and you can
make money on that. >> Yeah, there's
that's great. Okay. >> You want to start
also feathering your nest if you're
101. Look for high quality kitchen wear,
kitchen knives. I have all kinds of I
love to cook, so I have all kinds of great
Hinkle knives. La Cuset, which is
wildly expensive when you go buy it new.
>> Oh, believe you me, it's very expensive.
Yes. >> So, I have a piece like this
one here I bought at a garage sale for
$5. Okay. >> And it retails for about 75,
you know, and so you can find really good
deals if you know what you're looking
for. >> Yeah. >> The whiskey glasses
in the front were real fine. and and a
friend friend of mine and I like our
cigars and whiskey once a month and then we
you know >> that's pretty cool >> have
a nice evening then we have to burn our
clothes but um
>> did I want to see that in in my mind
>> yeah well not outside >> okay okay
not so sure I understand all of that
okay >> but uh I found >> but these are
beautiful glasses >> fun and I thought
they were so cool looked at them they're
marked laik paid I happily paid
the $10 a piece they retail for 250
a piece. >> No way. >> Yeah. So, you
can find >> steels when it comes and
then I like to cook and so these things
here are kind of odd. Well, I have a lot
of copper wear cuz I like the de and
that kind of falls into the decorating
thing too. You can decorate with
it. >> Uh >> show them this. This is
incredible. >> This muffin pan. This
is a a specialty pan. I never would buy
that new. It runs around I can't remember
$75 to $100 new. But for eight bucks,
I'll buy it. And um I've I've
already burnt several things in it.
>> And this is another one >> seems to
be a theme here. >> I'm burning things.
>> Okay.
>> And then this here was something I
found at a These are all things I found at
garage sales. >> Oh my. Oh no. >>
Oh no. We did it. But it actually
explains a point. So >> it does explain
a point. >> Quickly on this chocolate
mold. I' I've thought, oh, I always
wanted to try to do that. I've never um
>> but it's a beautiful piece. >> But
it's a beautiful So it hangs on my wall.
Someday I'll make chocolates and I'll
bring you something. >> Okay. >> Okay.
Here's the point of this, folks.
>> I can't believe I did this. >> Yeah.
>> Artwork. You can find really great
deals with art. >> Yeah. >> But also
look at the frames. The point of this one
was wasn't the picture. The point is the
frame, >> right? >> So many people have
art on their walls that's really horribly
ugly and that's all they see is the
art. >> Art, right? But really, they
love the frame of it. value is the frame.
So, next time um uh I'm going to take
this out. I'm going to put a mirror in it
and it'll be just outstanding. >> Yeah.
And >> I love the frame and like you
picked up this really cool art deco
frame with your friend that you put your
friend's picture in. >> I did and that
that was a little one I found and my dear
friend Crystal is in the artwork. And
then the other thing is is for the DYI,
there's a saying in in the business that
goes the early bird catches the worm,
right? So, everybody wants to be the
first in line. >> Sure. you know, and and
you'll >> So, you're saying get there
early. >> That's one way of doing it. The
other rest of the saying is is the
second rat gets the cheese. >> Oh, okay.
>> And so, oftentimes, especially if
you're a DIY and you're buying for
yourself, furniture and decor things
are dirt cheap the last day of the sale.
>> Yes, that's true. >> And so, you can
pick >> No one wants to deal with, you
know, getting rid of that, >> right?
And so, you can make great deals at the
end. >> Yeah. And also, I would say too,
there are lots of little things here
that may not be worth anything. But if
you have someone who's into arts and
crafts and all the fun that you can have
with different items like those pearls
and these things, these things too. >>
If you get a jar, see a jar of buttons,
buy them all. >> Oh, yeah. They're
great. There are some really fun crafts.
>> The old folks used to hide their
jewelry in buttons. >> Oh, really? >> Yeah.
So, so I've gotten gold earrings and and
things out of a jar of buttons. >> Oh,
wow. I did not know that. Look at you.
Okay. All great information. And I'm so
sorry about you, but at least you didn't
like what was in it. So, there's that.
>> Sorry, I ruined the show here. >>
You did not. You did not. I need more
information about your cigar night, though.
I need more. Okay. All right. Thanks
so much, Gary. Appreciate it. We'll be
right back with more AM Northwest. Don't
go away.